so now let us try our hand at some tree
height reduction suppose we have these
six instructions we are adding r1 and r2
putting the result in our 10 then
subtracting r3 from that then adding r4
then subtracting r5 then adding r6 and
then subtracting r7 if we now do a 3
height reduction on this what do we get
and I already pre-populated most of the
answer for you so we're still gonna add
r1 and r2 and put the result in our 10
but then what do we add input in our 11
what do we add our 11 to and put that in
our 10 what do we then add up and put
the result in our 11 and then we add our
7 to what and put the result in our 11
and finally we will subtract our 11 from
our 10 and get the final result in our
10 and this should be the same result
that we got here so the question for you
is what should be in these five places
and also the ILP here is clearly 6
cycles for 6 instructions which gets us
a 1 why well because each of the
instructions depends on the previous one
with your new tree height reduced code
what is the LP we still have six
instructions how many cycles do we need
to do them now